MICHELLE KAPLAN

Software Engineer | Denver, CO

SUMMARY

Software engineer who loves to build and create! Experience working with cross-functional and global teams, utilizing my excellent communication skills to communicate goals and objectives. Empathetic to the user and understand the user journey and implementation of human centered design.

CONTACT DETAILS

• Phone: 303-519-0805

• Email: michellekaplandev@gmail.com

GitHub: michellekaplan7LinkedIn: kaplanmichelle

SKILLS

Object Oriented Programming: JavaScript (ES5, ES6), React, React Hooks, Redux, HTML, CSS/Sass, iQuery

Test Driven Development: Mocha, Chai, Jest, React Testing Library

Tools: Webpack, Travis Cl, Postman, Netlify, Heroku, Fetch, Axios, NPM

UI/UX: Wireframing (Adobe XD, Miro, InVision), Accessibility

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software & Design | Denver, CO

Jan. 2020 to Aug. 2020 Front End Engineering

Colorado State University | Fort Collins, CO

Aug. 2013 to Dec. 2016

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration

- University Honors Student, Cum Laude
- Concentration: Marketing, Strategic Marketing Certificate

• GPA: 3.877

EMPLOYMENT

Nanno | Denver, CO - Remote

Software Engineer | Sept. 2020 to Dec. 2020

- Modernized a Rails monolithic app into a progressive web app
- Built a React/Redux front-end and integrated it to a new back-end
- Designed and implemented testing strategy for front-end components
- Collaborated with other team members with an agile approach
- Lead and participated in technical design meetings, pair programming sessions and code reviews
- Wrote understandable, testable code with an eye towards maintainability and scalability

Cochlear Americas | Centennial, CO

Services and Marketing Specialist | July 2018 to Oct. 2019

- Developed paid Facebook campaigns that resulted in over \$80,000 of revenue
- Created and implemented a newsletter strategy, aiming to increase engagement and open rates for 55,000 recipients
- Managed the production of recipient testimonial videos, including editing, approval, publishing, and marketing
- Managed the scholarship program, awarding 8 people \$2,000/year, up to 4 years

Services and Marketing Coordinator | Sept. 2017 to July 2018

- Managed social media, newsletters and blog calendars, including writing Facebook/Twitter posts through Spreadfast
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to manage the production of both print and digital assets

PROJECTS

Additional work at: https://alumni.turing.io/alumni/michelle-kaplan

Find My Market - React Native / Expo

GitHub / YouTube Demo | August 2020

- Mobile (iOS) geolocation app built to help find farmers markets within a 50 mile radius from the users location
- Full-stack team project using React Native, React Native Maps, React Hooks, Expo, Jest, React Testing Library

Wizard Harry - React / Router

GitHub / Deployed Application | June 2020

- Website for Harry Potter fans to get advice from Hermione, be sorted by school, and view/save/sort spells
- Solo project using JavaScript, React, Router, Jest, React Testing Library, fetch API, PropTypes, local storage